CHRISTOPHER WATSON

Sacramento ♦ 510-502-5046 ♦ chewatson@outlook.com
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/chewatson/
Portfolio: https://github.com/ChCWatson/Portfolio

SUMMARY

An analyst with a background in economics and business operations, with a certificate in Cybersecurity from the University of California - Davis, and a CompTIA Security+ certification. An effective problem solver who brings both technical aptitude and an understanding of business processes. A Computer science enthusiast with hands-on experience with cyber security practices in Windows and Linux environments and programming knowledge with Python and C++.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C++, Python, SQL, HTML

Operating System: Linux, Kali Linux, Windows

Tools: Burp Suite, Hashcat, Metasploit, Wireshark, Snort, Azure Labs, Splunk

EDUCATION

University of California - Davis

Certificate - Cybersecurity

March 2022

University of California - Davis

(B.S) Bachelor of Science - Managerial Economics

December 2018

CERTIFICATIONS

CompTIA Security+

April 2022

PROJECTS

Red Vs. Blue Team Project

Summary: As the Red Team, you will attack a vulnerable VM within your environment, ultimately gaining root access to the machine. As Blue Team, you will use Kibana to review logs taken during their Day 1 engagement. You'll use the logs to extract hard data and visualizations for their report.

Role: Pentester and SOC Analyst

Tools: Azure Labs, Kali Linux, ELK Monitoring, Kibana

ELK Stack Project

Summary: Configure an ELK stack server in order to set up a cloud monitoring system.

Role: Cloud Network Administrator

Tools: Azure Labs, Docker, ELK stack, Playbooks

Penetration Test and Report Project

Summary: Performed a penetration test on GoodCorp Inc's CEO's workstation using a virtual disk image as a copy of the workspace to identify vulnerabilities and recommend improvements to network security.

Role: Pentester

Tools: Kali Linux, Metasploit

WORK EXPERIENCE

Beer40 Community Taphouse

Vacaville, CA

General Manager

July 2020 - Current

- Analyzing and reporting on financial data
- Creating and managing yearly budgets
- Employee and Contractor Payroll
- Product Price strategies
- Hiring and training Employees
- Researching product market trends of consumers
- Manage social media and website

SacYard Community Taphouse

Sacramento, CA

General Manager

January 2018 - Current

- Exercising leadership and problem-solving skills to maintain team efficiency
- Optimizing labor costs and increasing sales by implementing a new Point of Sale software
- Developing and fostering working relationships with vendors and affiliates
- Managing accounts payable using QuickBooks
- Employee scheduling and payroll

Awards:

- C.A.A.P.S Small Business of the Year, 2018
- East Sacramento Chamber of Commerce New Business of the Year, 2018
- Best of Sacramento Best Place to get a Beer, 2019

Cabrillo Community College

Aptos, CA

Facility and Event Coordinator

January 2012 - October 2015

- Tracked and documented operational and financial records to perform quarterly analysis of performance and costs
- Implemented a new internal and external rental software to improve operational procedures
- Drafted facility contracts and liability agreements
- Conducted and analyzed market research to establish a cost-effective pricing structure

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE & ACTIVITIES

Third Option Investments

Founder / Vice President / Treasurer

- A general partnership agreement to contribute money to a pooled fund for investments.
- An organization that educates its members on market trends, stock/option trading strategies and cryptocurrencies.

INTERESTS & SOFT SKILLS

- Customer Service
- Multi-tasking
- Managerial Experience

- Data Analysis
- Accounts Payable
- Restaurant Management